hi welcome to the eev blog an
Electronics engineering video blog of
interest to anyone involved in
electronics design I'm your host Dave
Jones hi it's e-reader review time now
uh as you may know some time back I
reviewed the new Amazon Kindle 3 when it
came out that was a very popular review
and tear down so I thought I'd have a
look at this new I River story HD it's
just come out on in Sunday in the US not
available in Australia yet but one of my
viewers John Chandler thanks John he
picked me one up it came out on Sunday
when it came out and fedexed it to me we
have it for review and tear down is it
as good as the Amazon Kindle 3 which is
its clear competitor let's find out and
we'll do a quick unboxing here now
here's the box and it's very reminiscent
of the Amazon Kindle box which I so
loved and here it is it's got the same
sort of uh you know plain packaging
recycled cardboard look although nowhere
on there does it say that it's actually
uh recycled cardboard at all whereas
Amazon do actually claim that and Amazon
have this great frustration free
packaging I love it you just all you do
is you uh ZIP the uh the cardboard cord
across like that and you open it up no
tools required fantastic but can't say
the same thing with the IR River story
HD there's just tape on the side like
this and to open it up shock horror I've
got to actually get my knife out get it
in there and slice the thing open how
offensive let's not quibble over the
packaging let's see what we have inside
shall we open it up Tada no got to open
up again Tada there it is and of course
you would think just like the Kindle you
would think it's already switched on but
it's not that is all you would think
that was like a some sort of some sort
of um act some sort of protective
display on the front of the actual unit
itself comes in the plastic like that
but it's not it's the eink display it's
the gorgeous eink display which takes no
power which is why they can actually uh
ship it with an image on the display
like that and from behind the camera I
didn't see this nice little tab here
which allowed you to just pull up the
unit like that excellent I like it and
what have we got under the bottom of the
box here to we've got a USB that's a
mini B uh mini connector so obviously
that's what's on there and we've got uh
some sort of quick use guide how we have
we the basics there you go setting up
your story HD how to plug it in ETC
forign stuff we don't need that we're
going to take a look at the actual um
story HD device itself now you may have
notied this barcode Inside the Box it
was just sitting loose on top but it's
actually an RFID tag if you can see
inside there there's actually a chip and
the antenna coil in there it's one of
those RFID tags now if you remember my
tear down of the uh Kindle it actually
had an RFID tag built inside the actual
unit itself whereas I don't know I
haven't torn down this one yet yet uh
we'll have to see but obviously it it
most likely hasn't because they had to
ship a separate tag with it and having
an RFID tag like this in inside the
actual box it allows them to uh scan
during the production process scan the
actual uh unit and figure out which uh
serial number is there and all sorts of
stuff so they've obviously uh allocated
this barcode to this particular serial
numbered uh unit and here it is compared
to the Amazon Kindle 3 cuz that is the
natural comparison obviously it's a
clearly a a competing unit it's almost
exactly the same size it is a little bit
um it is a little bit wider than the
Kindle like that but it's almost
identical uh length there's no
difference there at all and thickness ah
there's not there's bugger all in that
as well they're they're basically the
same thickness so really there's not
much difference between them and the
display are virtually identical size
except of course the story The Big
Marketing point of the story HD is that
it claims to have 60% more pixels or a
HD display compared to the well they
don't mention the uh Kindle but they
compare to other competing ebook readers
which of course they mean the Kindle 3
and I don't know I prefer the charcoal
finish of the Kindle 3 over this this
one's a bit flashy we've got these uh
sort of uh copper colored uh buttons I
would probably say they are and there's
no uh controls on the side there's no
page turning controls like you had on
the Kindle so um I've never used an
iiver uh story device and iiver e-reader
before so I have no idea how to even
turn the displays I guess I'm going to
find out and if we take a closeup look
at the quiry keypad here it's in the
straight alignment as per the uh Kindle
I don't know that's not as um nice I
guess as the traditional uh spaced
keyboard they've got their four-way
looks like a four-way uh cursor bar here
which you obviously push up and down and
then click left and right and on the
bottom here we've got a USB mini B
connector now the Kindle has the micro
uh USB connected now um the mini is not
is not nearly as robust in the number of
uh insertion
as the micro USB connector used on the
Kindle so I guess if um that could
potentially uh wear out quicker but uh
there's nothing else on the bottom there
there's nothing on the top and if we
turn it over here it's a it's a rather I
don't know if it's a nice brown type of
uh color on the back but there you go
there's a story HD with the FCC stuff
the specs and uh basically down here
here's our power button which we slide
across and uh there's really not much
else designed by IR River of course and
this looks
like this looks like the SD card slot
there it is you lift it up and bingo oh
it's got a nice little uh hinged
attachment here which just flips out of
the way that's really nice and it's a
standard SD card of course that is one
of the major things lacking on the
Kindle is expansion capability now I am
surprised they've gone with a standard
uh SD instead of a Micro SD but I think
that's really good on a product of this
physical size there is really no need to
go to the micro um micro SD card format
it's great for mobile phones and things
like that but when you got a product
this big really you should just be stand
using standard SD and they've done that
and I think that's terrific but uh of
course there's no one of the things
lacking which is on the Kindle is a
headphone socket you can actually
play uh music and you can get talking
books and things like that the I River
doesn't have that that's pretty
disappointing not that I've ever really
used it but I'm sure there might be a
lot of people who use the audio
capabilities of the Kindle let's switch
it on and see what we get we just have
to slide the button here which is uh
once you get to know that it's under the
bottom I guess you can just uh slide it
like that which is quite good it's uh
better than I think it's probably better
than the one on the edge on the Kindle I
don't know the the boot time
is H I guess because it's the first time
we literally the first time I've ever
switched this on there we go it's got to
go through a setup process there um
which I think the Kindle had to do as
well so I I'll have to link my uh my
Google Books account with this thing
that's not done whereas the Amazon
Kindle when it ships if you because you
order it directly from Amazon uh it it
already comes preconfigured with your
account and your name information you
can do that online before you actually
get it so when you actually take it out
of the box and switch it on it says you
know hello David and uh it's already
registered for you there you go welcome
to your I River story HD press enter to
confirm
Tada and it's updating and there we go
it's uh it's it's on it's ready to go so
let's switch that off
again there we go it uh just like the
Kindle it comes up with a um some sort
of random picture I'm not sure if that's
a same every time I'd like to think that
it actually changes and let's switch it
on and bingo that switches on very
quickly I like it and it actually
shipped with a reasonable amount of
battery life left and by default it
comes with the uh sign in thing here
which I'll have to do and it says what
book you're currently reading by the
looks of it and it looks like it does
come with a couple of books populated
there's no extra uh page there but it
looks like it does come with excellent
The Time Machine by HG worlds now let's
scroll down here now you have to use
this uh
scroll uh this four-way joystick kind of
button here and wh that popped to the
end the time machine okay how do we do
that I guess we go enter probably too
bad if you're uh left-handed perhaps
because the enter button over here
whereas this only has home and back so
if you're using it with your left hand
um I figure you would have to come in
here with your right hand and press
enter
but uh with your right hand here you can
hold the thing in one hand you can
scroll around like that I don't mind
this uh four-way joystick so far
actually my first impression is
reasonably quite good it works
reasonably well there's a reasonable
height on it so that your thumb can
actually uh get it like that it actually
get good purchase on the button I kind
of like that but let's press enter and
see if we can go into the time machine
load
in HG worlds love it
beautiful The Time Machine by HG worlds
and I assume this is how you scroll the
pages this is a digital copy of book
that was preserved for
generations
and once again that seems to be like a
scanned version of the book it doesn't
seem to be oh no there we go we've
gotten into proper text but looks of it
and there we go if you take a look up at
the top right corner up here there's a
tiny little number four that shows that
we're on page four of the book and it's
absolutely tiny they have made that as
minuscule as possible based on the the
higher resolution of this display you
really can't see that if you were
visually impaired you would never be
able to see that it's crazy so really
that's one of the disadvantages I guess
of having a higher resolution display is
that when you're a designer like this
you are temp Ed to actually use the
resolution of that display and that's
just crazy I can barely read that and
I've got perfect eyesight I'm currently
on page six there and watch like I go
from page five there it is up there a
tiny five up there I'll jump to page six
and it jumps to there the position the
page indicator and I jump to page
seven there we go and it's down here
what's going on there it just seems to
jump I got down a page 12 and it's just
jumped up to the top again Crazy by
default I think it's just it's just
hasn't got the contrast that the Kindle
seems to have and if we zoom in here and
take a look at the uh take a look at the
text here I mean I'm sure we can change
the font on the ey River and the font
size and things like that but I just
much prefer looking at the Kindle
display at first glance here let's have
a look at what they claim here on the
back of the IR River box fast page turns
using cortex CPU great well let's try it
out shall we now I've got a very large
ebook on here and I'm like 90% of the
way through it so I'm near the end of an
ebook here and I'm right at the start if
that matters I'm not sure but I'm right
at the start of the time machine here on
the IR River and let's do a page
turn no that's pretty Bo that's slow
that was slow slower
there well if anything it's slightly
slower than the kind do I think it's
certainly not better so I don't know
about that claim there about
faster page turns it's certainly not
faster than the competition faster than
the previous I River maybe but otherwise
nope now one of the great things about
the Kindle I loved is that you could use
it either left or right-handed single
hand like this and if I'm sitting in bed
or I'm sitting in the bathtub or
something and I'm reading my Kindle here
I can page I can hold it like this and
Page forward and page back even with
either my left hand or my right hand
with the buttons on the side that you
can just use up and down so you can use
it both left and right-handed but yeah I
don't think I want my thumb in that
position I don't know it's just a
personal preference thing I guess you'd
get used to it I'd have to use it for a
long time to see how beneficial that is
but if you scroll down you actually uh
turn to the the next page if you scroll
up you turn to the previous page so it
can be used both left and right-handed
that's all right let's pop up the option
menu on both of the
units it pops up slightly quicker on the
Kindle and uh you can navigate of course
you've got to navigate using the square
controller down here now this is where I
do actually prefer this uh quite nice um
joystick large joystick style button on
the IR River that's one of its
advantages when you going through menus
and selecting things like that but as I
said the enter buttons over here the uh
Kindle one is in the center so you know
there's there's not much between them
really but um I find that uh the Kindle
they've got it right look big nice
readable menu like that huge massive the
I River they're taking advantage they
trying to take advantage of that high
defin display and they've made the font
smaller it's not nearly as readable I
don't like it as much here's one thing I
don't like with their menu system if I
pop it up here okay and let's say we
want to adjust the text size there press
enter and I've decided no I want to I
didn't want to do that I wanted to go
back to the option menu you can't just
press option to take you back it's crazy
you think okay there's a back button
over here great you press the back
button no it takes you back to the book
anyway let's take a look at the text
adjustment size here so we'll adjust
text size and bingo you can
adjust the size of the text and it does
actually do it in real time on the
display there not particularly quickly
it actually takes quite a while to cycle
through the larger fonts like that but
that's not bad at all now I'm not sure
if I'm going to be able to get this on
camera but if you can see there there is
a ghost image there left behind from the
menu I'm trying to going to try and get
it here if I get the right angle it it
it actually really is quite visible and
if I call up the option display again
just look you can see the a you can see
that box and the a button there if I go
in again and go into the menu there it
is you can see it and if I go
back like
this
it remains there's a ghost image there
it's you do get a little bit of that on
the Kindle but it's not it's not as bad
as the iiver so I think the ghos in is
worse on this display now I'm in the
option menu here and really I can't find
anywhere to change the type of font you
can change the size of font but you
can't change the type I think that's
ridiculous um it doesn't have a rotation
sensor in there so it doesn't
automatically flip around but it does
have a dedicated button which the Kindle
doesn't have you have to go through a
menu to actually get to that and here's
that annoying thing again if you're I'm
still in the text size menu and I can't
just go and press that I've got to
actually press back to go back to there
and then I can press the rotate uh menu
but it only calls up the menu it doesn't
actually let you uh actually choose a
default position that I'm aware of and
it's rotated it like that there you go
um but it would be nice if you could
have a preset rotation and then you just
hit that and it toggles between the two
of your preferred orientations and
there's that ghosting on the display
again the e in display it clearly hasn't
uh dropped all of the uh all of the
whatever they are like carbon crystals
or something all the way to the bottom
and you can see it you can see the ghost
ghosted text on there and that's that's
no good at all I don't like it one of
the great features I love about the
Kindle is that you can highlight
passages of the book and you can share
that with other people and likewise here
it actually shows that eight people
eight other people have highlighted this
particular sentence in the in the book
itself and I can add to that and uh you
can actually switch that um on or off
but that's quite nice and the IR River
really doesn't have a nice uh
functionality like that I kind of miss
it I really liked that
interactiveness of the Amazon Kindle you
could just share your reading experience
with other people the I River doesn't
seem to be the same one of the great
things about these ebooks is that they
have dictionaries built in so if you
don't know what a word means then you
can just uh call it up now let's try it
on the iiver here we've got dictionary
let's select that and takes a second or
two but it pops up it's got the Collins
English dictionary in it New Edition for
advanced Learners there you go but it
looks like you can't just scroll around
the document and highlight a word it
looks like you've got to type it in the
Kindle on the other hand is much nicer
you don't have to enter any mode at all
all you've got to do is just move the
cursor around like this and you can
scroll around the document Let's uh look
at the word science there and it's
automatically popped up the top with the
definition for the word science but hey
let's give it a go anyway I've typed in
the word science I press enter
and what's it going to do well it takes
its time and there we go it's a really
it's a full-on dictionary there you go
it's a little bit more comprehensive
than the Kindle but really I much prefer
this um just the cursor uh live
scrolling capability of the Kindle to
this one and the great thing about the
highlights feature in the Kindle is that
you can actually view all of the
highlights in the book that that other
people have actually um that have
actually highlighted and Bingo and there
they are and you can just scroll down
and you can jump directly to the
location in the book there's no
competing capability on the iriv that I
can find so far let's see what we've got
back at the home menu if you press home
you get back to the main screen and
let's press the options button and see
what we get just like the Kindle you can
turn the wireless offer on I haven't set
that up yet you can go to the Google
ebook store
which uh we'll see later how if that's
any better than well it's hard to judge
whether it's better than the Amazon
Kindle Store you know there once again
there are going to be books that are
available on one that aren't available
on the other and there will be ones that
are available on the same store and
their different prices etc etc but
Google have a lot of free ebooks
probably more uh free ebooks than the
Amazon Kindle perhaps that's one of
their claims to fame fame you can
refresh your books you can uh do do
bookmarks uh it's not the same as
highlighting searches you can call up
the dictionary straight away sign into
to Google and settings that's what I'm
interested in let's go down here and
have a look Wireless controls system
settings personal information power
settings system Wizards device
information Wireless controls system
settings personal information power
settings system Wizards device
information let's set that auto sleep
settings I'm not sure what the
difference between uh power off and
sleep is but I guess we'll find that out
in due course but it's set for 15
minutes so let's go back if we can press
the back button it does get us back to
the previous menu uh personal
information system settings let's see
what we have in here we have date and
time I'll have to set that for Sydney
Australia because I got this from the US
uh English of course they probably got
different languages in there Library
View options and that's about all um
that's not terribly exciting at all and
if you go into the wireless controls up
here it does actually have an airplane
mode which I guess if you got those uh
fussy flight attendants you can switch
it to airplane mode but a lot of them
don't understand um these ebook readers
they don't actually do anything uh
they're not actually running when
they're just sitting there on the page
so it's unless you actually have I mean
airplane mode would switch the wireless
off but why you can't just you would
switch the wireless off anyway most of
the time because it it's just going to
chew your power so really I don't
understand why they've got an air an
airplane mode like that they should just
have uh Wireless off and on I just went
into the wireless network there and I
had no problems at all just typed in my
password for uh my wireless network and
it worked a treat it connected straight
away no problems whatsoever and it's got
a tin in the little wireless icon up
there once again it's pretty darn small
and so is the time up there they've
really they've they've got to make those
these uh symbols on the display bigger
the menu options and things like that
they're not as readable as they are on
the Kindle and they're both pretty
identical when you call up the menu when
you're reading a book you've got the uh
once again you've got the title of the
book up here which I like but once again
it's a really small font harder to read
the time's not as easy to read and uh
the battery symbol is is probably easier
to read on the iriver that's about the
only thing that they actually got uh
right there and this is interesting look
what's just popped up uh after I
connected to the network you know 5
minutes 3 to 5 minutes after I connected
it's said a system update is available
would you like to download the system
software updates you bet let's give it a
go oh problem connecting to the W ah
what what give me a break I didn't even
give me a chance what's going on well
I'll try and sign into my Google account
presumably it's my standard Google
account and uh see what we can do here
here's one feature I really like and I
really think they've got right just like
on the Kindle they've got a symbol
button here which uh which swaps between
uh letters and numbers and other you
know at symbols and things like that
when you're typing stuff in like uh
passwords and you're typing in email
addresses if we press symbol what
they've come up with is there's a direct
one toone vertical mapping of the keys
like that so it shows you how they
overlay so if we want to type in one
like that we just press that and it
highlights it up there it really is
quite nice to get that vertical
reference position so you can actually
just you just visually scroll down with
your eyes and you know exactly by
looking at that mapping which button to
press I really like it it works quite
well and if you compare that with the
symbol name on the Kindle it just pops
up with that and you've got to scroll
around and then press enter it's not
nearly as usable as the iiver big thumbs
up for to iiver for the getting that one
right I tried to sign in and look I
can't and I've double and triple checked
my um Gmail username and password crazy
I don't know what's going on is it
because I'm an Australian and ites
doesn't let me do this I can get into
Google Books no problems at all through
my Gmail account on the main computer
but it does not let me sign in here
don't know what's going on at all and I
think I might have found my problem here
look I've logged into Google Books in my
Google account and it says you have not
linked your Google profile to your
Google Books account go figure so it
looks like I'm going to have to do that
okay let's give that a try here we go I
guess I click on this button here your
profile has been connected refresh the
page to see it Beauty all right let's
refresh and see what we
get taada we're up I think maybe I
should be able to log in now let's give
it a go I tried it again and well no
nothing username password you entered is
incorrect please try again I'm sick of
trying again just W and what do you know
I try a different browser I've opened
the Google Books in here and it tells me
the latest Google ebooks are not
available for sale in your location yet
but I can happily uh do whatever I want
and effortlessly and uh read them
effortlessly across my device as well
it's not very effortlessly if it doesn't
let me log into the thing and look
here's the ad for the IR River story
HD learn more let's click on that Google
ebook e-reader oh look yeah that's great
I've got one in my hands and I can't log
into the damn thing
crazy well if we can't sign into the
stupid Google ebook system then I'll um
copy some eBooks over manually I've put
them got them on the SD card here let's
pop it in there and I assume it goes up
that way there's nothing to tell you
otherwise no it must it goes up the
other direction there you
go and does it pop up with anything yes
it
does no it popped up with something
there but I can't see them on the main
screen here so I'm not sure how to find
them at all I found it it's a bit
nonobvious but by default uh you're on
this Google library tab here and there
are different tabs recent favorites
title and author and if you scroll the
cursor I don't really necessarily like
the shape of that cursor either or the
bar here here but anyway if you scroll
over to recent Bingo we've got some uh a
mix of basically a recent ones I've
opened but the here are where the SD
card ones popped up I I actually had two
uh I downloaded from Google ebooks a
free one Frankenstein and uh in both the
Epub format and PDF format and you can
see it tells you where it is it's on the
SD card there document so I think it uh
can it can certainly recognize PDF let's
see if we can actually read it uh I've
got another book down here the complete
guide to Natural Health in PDF format
let's try that one and see what happens
takes a little bit to open the book for
the first time I don't know exactly know
what it's uh doing there here we go and
uh there we go it uh reads PDFs no
problem at all but of course it's um
format added in a certain size and it
won't automatically um expand that out
to actually fill the screen so the PDF
because PDF is a page-based uh format
it's it's not like an ebook format that
can uh flow the text through of course
that's not going to be nearly as good as
the eepb format although the high
resolution screen is granted it it is
very very good so you can it is better
than the Kindle for reading PDFs in
fixed page format that are actually too
big for this uh screen so it is it it is
excellent for actually doing that
there's one thing I do like about uh
reading the PDFs on here when you scroll
through it shows you the page number and
the total number of pages I would prefer
if that actually stayed there um like it
does on the uh Kindle the Kindle gives
you a percentage it doesn't give you a
page uh number for something like that
but I yeah I just much prefer if it
stayed there but anyway that is quite
handy to tell you your progress through
the book every time you turn the page
now I was finally able to zoom in on
that PDF a bit more but it was very slow
and very clunky so I wasn't impressed
with that uh in in the least but it has
actually allowed me to uh no there we go
Bingo it's automatically popped back so
that's useless you can't even keep looks
like you can't even keep that particular
Zoom ratio and uh and go through pages
like that automattic switches back to
full page view crazy but curiously if I
turn an option called Reflow on here I'm
not exactly sure what it is but if I
actually do that then it does actually
give me the adjust the traditional
adjust text size thing here but it
doesn't actually work doesn't actually
do
anything and for the electronics people
out there I've got a PDF data sheet in
here let's and give that a go shall we
that's a typical data sheet which would
be uh A4 formatted and there it is it
you can actually read it it it it's not
bad at all um it's quite small of course
and uh zooming in is a pain in the butt
but that's that's not too bad you can't
actually read data sheets on there I
rather like that whereas on the Kindle
it was the resolution wasn't quite
as good it was almost there this one
seems to be just there it just does it
there's one thing I'm not sure if I like
or not but I've got Wireless switched on
at the moment and if we switch switch it
off there we go it looks like it comes
up with just the same uh screen there
I'm not sure if you could get in there
and uh change it maybe if you root the
thing or something like that I don't
know but uh you turn it back on and it
automatically switches the wireless off
for you well that's all right I guess
power saving feature but I don't know it
might annoy the hell out of you if you
really want uh the Wi-Fi on when you
switch it on and of course if you switch
it off and then back on it does actually
uh come back exactly where you were
before and it's not just inside the uh
book either it's um actually uh menu
options and entering in your password
and things like that if you switch it
off it does revert to exactly the same
spot as you'd expect and there you have
it that's about all the there is to the
iriver story HD it's just a basic eBook
reader and it does nothing more it
doesn't have like an extra web browser
it doesn't have text to speech or any of
those niceties that are on the Kindle
but I guess it does a reasonably good
job of reading a book whether or not the
user interface is exactly as good well
that's up to personal opinion really
okay let's see what happens when we plug
it into our PC for the first time
standard mini B connector no problems
USB connect connected there it is and
it's charging the battery well it you
can select between either charge battery
or connect removable disc I'm assuming
that uh it will still charge if you're
connecting to the removable disc or at
least I would hope so and I was hoping
that it would actually uh give you
access to the internal drive as well I'm
assuming it does but maybe if you've got
the SD card in there we'll find out USB
connected it hasn't oh
yep currently reading oh what's going on
up updating your story HD was doing
something well there it is it's
certainly charging from the USB or it's
uh claiming too as you'd expect but uh I
tried to connect that in storage mode it
said asked me to connect to the um
external card and I expected it to show
up as a mass storage device in Windows
Explorer but it doesn't aha it looks
like I got it I removed the SD card and
I reconnected it and sure enough device
driver software was not successfully
installed but it has popped up with
story HD as the drive so there's
something with having that SD card in
there that didn't work but here it is we
can access the internal system drive and
these are the folders with inside our um
story HD there's the system thing it's
got a whole bunch of system files I
don't know what they are Thum no idea
what that is but uh if we go in there
image folder empty don't know what that
is maybe you can put images in there
comic once again empty no idea
book download there you go that's where
it's downloaded the books in ePub format
they're the ones that came uh
pre uh pre-installed on the story HD so
presumably I can just start drag files
from my hard drive directly into there
and they will show up on the internal um
on the internal memory and manual
there's a user manual in here as well
which I eventually uh found that's a
user guide for the thing that's actually
comes pre-installed and Adobe Digital
Editions XML file not sure what that is
but there you go you can access the
internal drive no problems at all but
like I said when you're in this USB
connected mode um it just says USB
connected I'm not sure if it's actually
charging in that mode or not there's no
charge indicator up the top of the
display and I've put the SD card back in
and I I connected it up and finally it's
actually decided to pop up with the
removable disc there it is so it's not
the internal drive anymore it's actually
the uh it's actually the SD card which I
had there and it looks like it has
created a thumbnail subdirectory cuz
that wasn't on there I didn't create
that
and one really important thing for an
ebook reader is the weight cuz you can
actually get fatigue when you hold it in
your hand it's uh the iriver story is
206 G we'll compare that to the
Kindle 233 there we go so it's slightly
lighter that's a win but I just remember
this is the 3G Kindle so it does have
that uh 3G SIM card module in there plus
it's got speakers as well so you'd
expect it to weigh a bit more so it's
probably on par if you take out those
features and of course it wouldn't be
any fun unless we stuck the thing in the
fridge and see what happens to it at low
temperatures let's do it I've got the
Kindle in there as well I've got my
meter to log the temperature and uh
we'll give it we go let's give it I
don't know an hour or two see what
happens it's been a couple hours let's
check it
out oh it was 1.3 but let's go to the uh
minimum minus
1.5° C don't know Fahrenheit for you
Yanks but uh here it is oh it's feeling
a bit uh feeling a bit uh Frozen but
let's try it out let's switch it
on and yeah it's slowed down just like
on the Kindle eink display we found that
it actually goes slower at lower
temperatures so let's try and page up
is that slower I don't know it's hard to
tell but anyway
survived survived no problems at all
Beauty and there's that ghost in on the
display again it's terrible I actually
thought I was giving it a bit of a thump
around I was sort of giving it the old
uh twist test to see if it was um you
know as solid as the Kindle like this it
feels very it feels very on par and I
was giving it a bit of a whack and I
thought that actually came through uh sh
you know it came through with more
ghosting than it did before so I'm
whacking the thing on the back and uh
I'm not sure if that is actually causing
additional uh ghosting on there but it's
I just don't like it at all it's it's
almost a showstopper but when it comes
down to it ultimately it's about all
about reading a book and you really need
the flexibility of being able to change
the fonts and the size and the spacing
and all that sort of stuff and this is
it on the IR River HD you can change the
font size and that it that's it it's
fixed but look on the Kindle not only do
you get front size you get type face you
get line spacing words per line much
more flexible I wouldn't give this up
for quids and of course you have to read
these things at night now I've got my
lights completely turned off in the lab
here it's pitch dark and I'm using my um
very uh tiny little underpowered LED
light cuz I don't like having a hugely
bright light so it's deliberately
underpowered single LED Mighty bright
book Le reading light and uh under the
light here I it may be hard to get on
camera there but I swear the Kindle has
got better contrast it is more readable
than the ey River um in terms of display
reflection um they're very similar
there's not much difference in there I'd
say maybe the Eye river reflects a
little bit uh more annoyingly but um
yeah give me the Kindle so the text
specs on this thing well it's got an IMX
508 arm cortex processor but as you saw
it's really no quicker than the Kindle
in fact it might even be a little bit
Tad slower so really there's no point to
that it's got got uh 2 gig internal
storage SP space which is pretty
generous but it's got the big selling
point is that it's got the SD card up to
32 gig I believe uh SD HD card supported
so that's great for um putting huge PDFs
and stuff on there your whole PDF
document library or whatever but it's
only got a 6-in uh display same as the
Kindle but the Kindle comes in a 9in
model as well which is uh better but it
does have that HD high resolution
display which uh 1024 by7 68 you can
actually read uh PDFs closer you know in
more detail which is slightly better
than the Kindle supposed to have a 6 we
uh battery life or 14,000 page turns
pretty much on par with the uh Amazon
Kindle 3 so my verdict on the IR River
story HD eBook reader well compared to
the Kindle I was pretty darn
underwhelmed if I hadn't have used the
Kindle before I probably would have
thought this was the greatest thing
since sliced bread but I expected a bit
more I expected much faster performance
didn't get it if anything maybe even
slightly slower than the Kindle free
crazy uh but you can't change the font
size with these ebook readers it's all
about the visibility of the display that
gorgeous eink display contrast isn't
nearly as good on this compared to the
Kindle 3 not even close it's close but
you know it this one's much more
readable and you can change the font to
suit your particular taste you can't get
that here hopefully I'll fix that on an
update similar sort of battery life
battery life is key with ebook readers
um I don't have the 6 weeks to test it
but maybe if I do a tear down I'll be
able to uh do some battery measurements
on it compared to the Kindle or
something like that but expect the
battery life to be pretty good at 6
weeks but gee I don't know I expected
something it's got the SD card yeah
great okay but not a huge uh Advanced
comp especially when it doesn't have
audio building like the Kindle which is
the thing that sucks up a lot of space
if you had a lot of audio stuff on there
and the HD display technically okay for
reading uh PDFs and other stuff at
really high resolution but in the end
give me the contrast of the Kindle any
day of the week I ain't giving up this
for anything see
[Music]
you